让我们回到简单的双连杆机器人操纵器，我们在很早就看到了它们
Let's return to the simple two-link robot manipulator that we looked at much, much earlier
在课堂中。当我们第一次看到它时，我们对运动学感兴趣，就是这样
in the course. When we first looked at it, we were interested in the kinematics, that's
观察关节角度Q1和Q2与位置和方向之间的关系
looking at the relationship between the joint angles, Q1 and Q2 and the position and orientation
最后的效应器。现在我们要做的就是考虑
of the end effector. Now what we're going to do is to consider
这些链接已经有了质量，所以我已经放弃了质心的符号
that these links have got masses so I have dropped on the symbols for the centre of mass
每个链接。因此，我们考虑在实践中如何机械地工作：每个
of each of these links. So we think about how this works mechanically in practice: Each
link必须支持超出它的所有其他链接以及每个链接
link has to support all of the other links that are beyond it and each link of course
然后由它之前的所有链接支持。
then is supported by all the links that are before it.
因此，链路之间存在机械连接，并且一个链路的重量必须如此
So there is mechanically a connection between the links, and the weight of one link has to
由它之前的链接和之前的链接出生，依此类推。然后每个链接发挥作用
be born by the link before it and the link before that and so on. Every link then exerts
相邻链接上的力量和时刻。
a force and a moment on its neighbouring links.
因此，一种非常有用的方法可以考虑对每种力量和力矩起作用的力量和力矩
So a really useful way to consider the forces and moments that are acting on each of these
链接是绘制一个自由的身体图。我们所做的是断开不同的链接
links is to draw a free body diagram. What we do is we disconnect the different links
我们单独看待它们，它们是自由的身体。
and we look at them individually, they are free bodies.
每个环节都有一个质量和重力将以向下的力作用于该质量。
Each link has got a mass and gravity's going to act on that mass with a downward force.
机器人的底座将提供垂直向上的力来保持红色链接
The base of the robot is going to provide a vertical upward force to hold the red link
最后阻止它掉下来，绿色链接将提供向下的力量
up to stop it from falling down and the green link is going to provide a downward force
由于自身的重量，在红色链接的末尾。
on the end of the red link due to its own weight.
现在看看绿色环节，这里会有向上的力量，相等而且
Look now at the green link, there's going to be an upward force here, which equal and
与红色链接上的向下力相反。这是牛顿第三定律。所以，如果有
opposite of the downward force on the red link. This is Newton's third law. So if there
是红色链接的向下力是绿色链接的重量，并有一个向上
is a downward force on the red link is the weight of green link and there is a upward
强制绿色链接由红色链接提供以保持它。
force on the green link which is provided by the red link to keep it up.
现在有一个电动机提供一个驱动关节的时刻。它提供
Now there is a moment provided by the motor which is driving joint one. It's providing
用于阻止红色链环旋转的扭矩。同样地，还有一个扭矩
a torque to stop the red link rotating. And similarly there's a torque applied to the
绿色链接由两个电机联合阻止绿色环节旋转。然后那里
green link by the joint two motor to stop the green link from rotating. And then there
是一个反作用扭矩，来自该电机的相等和相反的扭矩，它被施加到红色连杆上。
is a reaction torque, equal and opposite torque from that motor which is applied to the red link.
所以在这里我们看到，所有的力和力矩都作用于每个机器人的链接。
So here we see, all the forces and moments that are acting on each of a link's of a robot.
这些力和力矩取决于每个链路的姿态，取决于链路的速度
These forces and moments depend on the pose of each link, depend on the speed of a link
和链接的加速度，当然，它们也取决于重力。
and the acceleration of the link and of course, they also depend on gravity.
这些力和力矩也取决于链接参数;链接的实际质量
These forces and moments also depend on the link parameters; the actual mass of a link
它的惯性和长度等等。那么让我们来看看其中的一些链接参数。
and its inertia and its length and so on. So let's have a look at some of these link parameters.
在运动参数中，我们在课程的前面介绍了很多，我们有链接
In kinematic parameters, we introduced much earlier in the course, we have the link
长度。在这种情况下，从关节轴1到关节轴2的长度A1。
length. In this case, the length A1 from the axis of joint one to the axis of joint two.
同样，我们有第二个链接的长度。
And similarly, we have the length of link two.
我们在这里介绍了链接坐标系。坐标框架1连接到末端
We introduced link coordinate frames here. Coordinate frame one is attached to the end
链路一和坐标框架2连接到链路二的坐标系。和我们
of link one and coordinate frame two is attached to the coordinate frame of link two. And we
当我们考虑串行链路时，我们再次查看链路坐标框架
looked at link co-ordinate frames again, much earlier when we were considering serial link
机械手运动学。
manipulator kinematics.
我们还可以描述质心相对于链接一个坐标的位置
We can also describe the position of the centre of mass with respect to the link one coordinate
帧。在这种情况下，它是C1在负X1方向上的位移。和我们
frame. In this case, it is a displacement of C1 in the negative X1 direction. And we
也有一个与质量M1的链接相关联的质量。
also have a mass associated with a link that's the mass M1.
然后我们也有惯性。这是链路相对于其中心的惯性
Then we also have an inertia. This is the inertia of the link with respect to its centre
质量和我们可以为链接二做同样的事情，距离链接两个坐标的距离
of mass and we can do the same thing for link two, the distance from the link two coordinate
框架到其质心和链节2相对于质心的惯性。
frame to its centre of mass and the inertia of link two with respect to its centre of mass.
所以我们现在有很多与每个链接相关的参数。对于每一个
So we have now quite a number of parameters associated with each of the links. For each
链接，我们有一个质量，我们有一个质量中心，在一般情况下将是一个
link, we have a mass, we have a centre of mass which in the general case would be a
由三个数字描述的矢量，我们有一个惯性矩阵。这是一个3x3矩阵和
vector described by three numbers and we have an inertia matrix. This is a 3x3 matrix and
如果我们考虑相对于质心的惯性，则3x3是对称矩阵。
if we consider the inertia with respect to the centre of mass, that 3x3 is a symmetric matrix.
现在，一个对称矩阵，而不是九个独特的元素，它只有六个独特
Now, a symmetric matrix, instead of having nine unique elements, its got only six unique
元素。总的来说，我们有十个参数来描述每个链接的动态。我们
elements. In total, we have ten parameters to describe the dynamics of each link. We
有一个质量，我们有三个翻译来描述中心的位置
have one mass, we have three translations to describe the position of the centre of
质量相对于链接坐标系，我们有六个对称的独特元素
mass with respect to the link coordinate frame, and we have six unique elements of the symmetric
惯性矩阵，相对于质心。
inertia matrix, with respect to the centre of mass.
因此对于第一个链路，那些参数是M1，质心是负C1
So for link number one, those parameters are M1, the centre of mass is negative C1 in the
X方向。其他两个元素为零，向量R1描述了该位置
X direction. The other two elements are zero, the vector R1, describes the position of the
质量中心。在这种情况下，它是负C1，Y和Z分量等于零。
centre of mass. And in this case, it's negative C1 and the Y and Z components are equal to zero.
我们有惯性矩阵，它只有一个元素，那就是惯性
And we have the inertia matrix which has only got one element and that is the inertia about
Z轴。现在在这种情况下，Z轴将从我们的页面出来。所以我们只有
the Z axis. Now in this case, the Z axis is coming at us out of the page. So we have only
一个有限元是IZZ1。
one finite element that's IZZ1.
对于第二个链接，它看起来有点类似。这些是每个的动态参数
For link two, it looks somewhat similar. These are the dynamic parameters of each of the
链接，有时也称为链接的惯性参数。到那个时刻
links, sometimes referred to as the inertial parameters of the links. When it comes to
描述运动物体的动力学，有许多不同的方法
describing the dynamics of moving bodies, there are number of different approaches that
我们可以采取，其中最常见的当然是牛顿第二定律，F=与之相关
we can take, one of the most common of course is Newton's second law, F = ma which relates
施加在身体上的力作为其质量的函数所经历的加速度。
the force applied to the body to the acceleration that experiences as a function of its mass.
对于旋转体，我们可以使用欧拉方程，该方程将施加在其身体上的扭矩联系起来
For a rotating body, we can use Euler's equation which relates the torque applied to its body
由符号tau给出的转动惯量J，它的角速率，欧米茄和
given by the symbol tau to its rotational inertia, J, it's angular rate, Omega, and
它的角加速度Omega点。
its angular acceleration Omega dot.
一种完全不同的方法是拉格朗日方程，它将动能和势能联系起来
A quite different approach is Lagrange's equation, which relates the kinetic, and potential energy
一个体的拉格朗日项的导数，T减去V，拉格朗日的导数
of a body to the derivatives of the Lagrangian term, T minus V, and the derivatives of Lagrangian
关于广义坐标和物体的广义速度
with respect to the generalized coordinates and the generalized velocities of the bodies
在机制中。
in the mechanism.
我们可以使用这些方法中的任何一种来分析串行链接操纵器的动态
We can use any of these approaches to analyze the dynamics of a serial link manipulator
但在本讲座中，我们将考虑牛顿-欧拉方法。这是一个组合
but in this lecture, we're going to consider the Newton-Euler method. This is a combination
牛顿定律描述平移运动和欧拉方程来描述旋转运动。
of Newton's law to describe translational motion and Euler's equation to describe the rotational motion.
一种非常简单而优雅的方法来确定串行链接机械手的动态运动
A very simple and elegant approach to determining the dynamic motion of a serial link manipulator
就是所谓的递归Newton-Euler算法。而且我不会全力以赴
is what's called the recursive Newton-Euler algorithm. And I'm not going to go into all
在这里，您可以在很多很多教科书中找到它，但我想要做的是
of the details here, you find it in many, many textbooks but what I'm want to do is
给你一个如何运作的直觉。
give you an intuition for how it works.
第一步是确定平移和旋转速度和加速度
And the first step is to determine the translational and rotational velocity and acceleration for
每个链接的质心。使用牛顿定律进行平移运动
the center of mass of each of the links. Use Newton's law for the translational motion
我们使用欧拉方程进行旋转运动。
and we use Euler's equation for the rotational motion.
我们从机器人的基础开始，我们向外工作，确定平移和
We start at the base of the robot and we work outwards, determining the translational and
每个链节的质心的角速度依次。一旦我们到达结束
angular velocity for the centre of mass of each link in turn. Once we get to the end of the
机器人，然后我们回到内部，然后我们确定力和力矩
robot, we then work our way back inwards and then we determine the force and moment that
每个链接都施加在更靠近机器人基座的链路上。这种方法
each link exerts on the link that's closer towards the base of the robot. This method
计算优雅，非常非常有效。
is computationally elegant and very, very efficient.
我将在MATLAB中创建一个双连杆机器人。为此，我将使用工具箱脚本
I'm going to create a two-link robot in MATLAB. To do that, I'm going to use toolbox script
mdl_twolink，这将在MATLAB工作区中创建一个名为two-link的机器人对象。
mdl_twolink and that will create in the MATLAB workspace a robot object called two-link.
这是一个拥有大量方法和属性的对象，我们将开始探索其中的一些。
This is an object that has great number of methods and properties and we'll start to explore some of these.
我们要看的第一个是绘图方法。所以对于机器人对象
One of the first ones we're going to look at is the plot method. So for the robot object
双链接，我们将调用绘图方法，以便点图调用绘图
two-link, we’re going to invoke the plot method so that’s dot plot invokes the plot
该对象的方法。我打算将它绘制为Q1等于零，Q2等于零。
method on that object. And I'm going to plot it for Q1 equal to zero, and Q2 equal to zero.
在这里我们看到机器人操纵器。不同于我们之前看过的那个
And here we see the robot manipulator. Unlike the one we looked at previously which operated
在XY平面中，我们可以看到这个双连杆机器人在XZ平面上运行。如此引力
in the XY plane, we can see that this two-link robot is operating in the XZ plane. So gravitational
沿Z方向的加速度作用于每个的质心
acceleration which is in the Z direction is acting on the centre of mass of each of the
这个机器人的链接往往会拉下它以使其崩溃。
links of this robot and will tend to pull it down to make it collapse.
我们可以使用递归Newton-Euler方程，我们可以使用rne方法
And we can use the recursive Newton-Euler equation and we can, which is the rne method
对于递归Newton-Euler。我可以问，如果这个机器人有什么扭矩
for recursive Newton-Euler. And I can ask, what are the torques on this robot if the
关节角度都等于零？所以这就是我刚刚策划的情况。
joint angles are both equal to zero? So that's a situation I've just plotted.
让我们说关节根本不移动，所以它们每个都有零速度
And let's say the joints are not moving at all, so they've got zero velocity each and
关节也没有加速。所以他们每个人都加速了零。
the joints are also not accelerating. So they've each got acceleration of zero.
它说Q1上的第一个关节上的扭矩是将它保持在这个位置所必需的
It says that the torque on the first joint on Q1 is necessary to hold it in this position
是19.62牛顿米，第二个关节的扭矩是4.9牛顿米。这使得
is 19.62 Newton meters and the torque on the second joint is 4.9 Newton meters. This makes
直觉我们。肩关节上的扭矩将大于扭矩
intuitive sense to us. The torque on the shoulder joint is going to be greater than the torque
在肘关节，因为肩膀必须支撑上臂和下臂，
on the elbow joint because the shoulder has to hold up the upper arm and the lower arm,
因为肘关节只需要撑住手臂的下半部分。
where as the elbow joint only has to hold up the lower part of the arm.
我们没有处理的是这两个扭矩的迹象，他们采取的行动方式。
What we don't have a handle on are the signs of these two torques, which way are they acting.
因此，一个很好的方法是使用不同的选项jvek重新绘制机器人。
So a good way to see that is to re-plot the robot using a different option which is jvek.
这表明每个关节的旋转访问。
What this shows is the access of rotation of each joint.
所以，如果我们记住我们的右手规则，以便了解积极的方向
So if we remember our right hand rule, in order to understand the direction of a positive
扭矩，我们做的是用右手抓住轴，将拇指指向方向
torque, what we do is grab the axis with our right hand, point our thumb in the direction
箭头和我们的手指在矢量周围卷曲，以指示正旋转的方向。
of the arrowhead and curl our fingers around the vector to indicate the direction of positive rotation.
我们在这里看到的是19.6的正扭矩作用在肩关节上
What we can see here then is that a positive torque of 19.6 acting on a shoulder joint
将是一个试图抬起机器人手臂的扭矩，这正是我们所做的
is going to be a torque that's trying to lift the robot arm up, which is exactly what we
对于联合二人来说，期望和类似
would expect and similarly for joint two.
所以递归Newton-Euler算法给了我们所需的扭矩
So the recursive Newton-Euler algorithm has given us the torques that are required for
机器人保持这种特殊的配置，其关节角度等于零和
the robot to stay in this particular configuration with both its joint angles equal to zero and
零关节速度和零关节加速度。这些是扭矩
with zero joint velocity and with zero joint acceleration. These are the torques that are
机器人必须处于此配置而不移动。
required for the robot to be in this configuration and not move.